All right. Uh, obviously we, uh, you
know, the weekend is not complete, but
we've got a little bit of a break or
really a long break here before, um, you
know, our last pick and then the
undrafted free agency process. Um, we're
really pleased with at least where we
sit. Um, you know, as we head into the
sixth round, um, you know, we expect by
the end of the weekend we'll be able to
add, you know, 10 rookies that we're
really excited about. Um, as well as,
you know, two future fourth round picks
in the 27 draft. you know, at the onset
of this or I guess you know, uh, last
week I talked about, you know, our goal
heading into the weekend is, you know,
not just the first round, but it's how
do we maximize the resources that we
head into the draft with, and that's
whether, you know, you're using those
resources, some of them for veteran
players, whether you're using it to
generate more by trading down, obviously
the players that you select, um, and
then the future draft capital that
you're able to to manufacture. So, we're
really pleased with where we sit today
with the combination of of players and
future assets that we're able to create.
Um, you know, we're looking forward to
finishing strong and um signing some
undrafted free agents that um you know,
can help our club this year. So, with
that, I'll open up for questions.
>> Drafting Jayen Green and just, you know,
what what's your thinking behind him and
what traits did you like about him?
>> Yeah, it was it's probably a little
similar to what I mentioned yesterday,
Mary Kay, where you know, at the
quarterback position, it's the most
important in sports. you know, we'll
we'll we'll make a bet or require a
player that we like if it's the right
cost. Um with Ton specifically, uh very
mature young man. Um really strong
makeup and he has rare physical gifts.
Um he has size, he has elite speed. Um
he has a big arm. Um you know, he's
going to need some polish with this
game. Uh but he has the work ethic and
he has the acumen to do so. So um we're
looking forward to adding him to the
roster and adding him to the mix in
terms of competition. Let's talk about
potentially moving Talon to wide
receiver or tight end. Given
>> we're not he's playing quarterback. He's
playing quarterback.
>> Andrew, when you talk, you talk about,
you know, polishing the turnovers were
obviously the big thing about his game
that seemed to be a red flag when he was
at Arkansas.
When you watch them on film, how much of
him I mean, do you see a pathway to
where he can work on that as he develops
at this level? Yeah, I I think context
is important with that type of thing,
Chris. You know, I think um you know,
Arkansas, they were actually one of the
the better offenses in college football
and faced I think it was like the
toughest slate of of college football
opponents. Um you know, with um you
know, the other side of the ball was was
not nearly as productive, you know, to
put it to put it kindly. And so I think
you as we've seen here when there's
maybe a little bit of undue stress
towards one side of the ball it can put
you in disadvantageous uh situations and
I think Talon had a fair amount of that.
That being said there are absolutely
areas of his game that he has to that he
has to clean up. Um but we are looking
forward to working with him and and
potentially developing him uh because he
does have a really strong makeup rare
physical gifts and then gifts and then
really the want to to improve. Andrew,
when you when you pick a quarterback
like this with this much just raw skill,
even if he's not ready to start or play
for you, can you find a way to use that
guy as a weapon when he's not your
>> Yeah. No, that's a good question. And I
think um so the short answer is yes. Um
obviously his gift as a ball carrier and
a runner is is pretty unique. Um, but it
does have to go within the whole, um,
you know, I guess it really has to go
with the offensive vision. And I think
that that's something that over the
course of the spring and into training
camp, um, as our offensive staff works
with, you know, this group of players,
um, you know, we'll define that identity
and figure out how much of that, you
know, we could incorporate, we could
potentially incorporate.
>> It doesn't.
>> Yeah, it doesn't it doesn't mean
anything. We're going to continue to
work with all those guys and um we like
having competition.
>> Compare like Taylor's to to Lamar
Jackson, but obviously knowing that Todd
has worked with like a really dynamic
quarterback, how much that maybe uh gave
you a little more comfort in making the
pick even though you acknowledge he's
going to need some polish.
>> Honestly, Daniel, it it had very little
to do with that. Um Todd's worked with
obviously he's worked with Lamar, but
Lamar was pretty unique relative to the
quarterbacks that he had worked with
previously. Um, I don't know that Lamar
and Stson Bennett could be more polar
opposite. Um, that's one of Todd's
gifts, the ability to maximize, you
know, offensive offensive skill sets
period. And particularly at that, you
know, at that spot. Um, you know, for us
it was as we looked at the prospects who
were available to us. Um, you know,
their relative strengths and weaknesses.
Um, you know, we felt like Talon was the
right pick at the top of six. Um, and
um, you know, look, we we're we're
excited to work with them.
years you guys have typically had four
quarterbacks at least in in the
offseason and throughout training camp
like what's what's the benefits for
defin
well part of it you needed to get
through I mean look we we lived it
firsthand last year right like you
needed to get through to get through
camp um you know we do believe in
keeping you know three on the active
roster and ideally a fourth on the
practice squad um but it's um you know
it's an important position there is um
you know attrition throughout the year.
Um, and I think also, you know, the the
other element is
it's never a problem to have too many
good players. You know, it just it just
isn't. Like even as I think through last
year with that position, um, you know,
we had two young guys, you know, two
vets who, you know, either got hurt or
um, you at one point were were no longer
the starter because of performance. um
and we were able to turn those, you
know, those players into to resources
that could help the team, you know, this
upcoming offseason. So, um sometimes
it's not a linear path in terms of how
they positively impact, you know, the
the roster of the organization. It may
not always be on field. Um but, you
know, we're going to try and make as
many, you know, calculated bets as we
can and um you know, take steps from
there. Andrew, um, going back to to
Kalin, the offense he played in at at
Arkansas, Bobby Batrino, also, you know,
kind of off of Daniel with with Lamar. I
mean, what does that offense do
specifically to kind of help a
quarterback prepare a quarterback to
kind of go I mean, can he is there
things that transfer from?
[clears throat]
>> I I I mean, I think there are a lot of
commonalities in college and pro
offenses. Um, you know, maybe I should
back up. There's only one Lamar Jackson,
you know, and so I understand the
thought or comparison there, but there's
one Lamar Jackson. Um, you know, I think
I think how Arkansas deployed Talon and
the run game, the QB driven run game,
you know, that's probably like the the
bigger, you know, the bigger component,
the, you know, the bigger similarity.
And, um, when you have someone with his
athletic gifts, you know, that's
something that you certainly want to
utilize within the offensive system. I
guess but kind of following up. I I mean
I guess it was more about what how
Patrino
prepares quarterbacks more so than a
direct comparison to to Lamar.
>> Yeah. I mean like you know his his his
track record speaks for itself. Um you
know that being said you know all these
quarterbacks who come into the NFL you
know this weekend they have a lot to
learn and you know fortunately we have
one of the best you know one of the best
teachers with you know with Todd and we
know he's in good hands.
>> 37 turnovers.
>> I'm sorry. How do you get past just the
37 turnovers in two two seasons?
>> Yeah. So, I think that goes with with
context, right? Like, um, you know, part
of it is, you know, is it a situation
where they're where they're down,
they're in heavy dropback, their passing
scores, and then part of it is like,
yeah, guys do need to take steps and
improve Tony. Um but the other side of
the coin is you know you do have you
know players who are able to generate
enough of enough explosive plays where
um a not a terminal but like maybe a
higher turnover rate is um at least more
doable for the team and that's what
Arkansas you know experience you know
probably a perfect example would be
maybe you know Josh Allen earlier in his
career um you know where he generated so
many explosive plays that you could live
with some of the errors now once he
became an MVP he was able to minimize
those with with time on task and
experience. But um you know at this
point in the draft there they're no
perfect prospects but um you know Tailon
has a lot of positives that make us want
to work with him.
>> It's a two-part question.
>> Um if Brford could beat out could win a
center job.
>> Would that be ideal for you and you can
move Jams to right guard?
>> I would say the thing that would be
ideal is just to have the best five out
there. Like I don't I don't I don't
really care who it is, you know, as long
as we have quality production at all
five spots.
>> If that would happen, the second part
would be having two rookies starting.
Would that be uh a little bit dicey?
>> I don't think so. I mean, the Patriots
had that and went to the Super Bowl this
year.
What do you like about um Joe Ber and
what I guess what's his outlook as he
you know comes in the door as far as
>> Yeah, Joe has size um really good hands.
Um he is a player that can produce both
in the Y, which is kind of your
traditional inline, you know, role, and
the F role, which is a little bit more
of a receiving role. Um so to have that
flexibility in the room, um is helpful
and important. Uh, so he was a guy that
we liked, we felt was, you know, there
for the value and, um, you know, we're
happy to add him to the team.
>> Andrew, did you ever think you were
going to make all four of those picks
that were so close together in the fifth
round?
>> Uh, we were ready to. I was hoping that
we wouldn't have to just because I
thought that look, there were players
that we like there. Um, but I thought
combination of some of the things that
we did were going to be more impactful
for the team.
When you look at the the versatility so
many of these guys that you guys have
drafted have, how much do you anticipate
that maybe playing into camp as they get
here of exploring other ways that they
might be used outside of their primary
role? Yeah, it's a um it's actually
honestly a little bit of a delicate
balance like you know Todd talks about
it all the time and um he's used some
other young players that he's coached
where the excitement can be while like
you know when we select this guy he can
do this he can do that he can do this
and you don't want to spread them too
thin through early. So you know we'll
probably um you know start them off in
in kind of one spot and let them get
their sea legs so to speak before you
know branching out. Um but it it's
certainly something that we're excited
about as we move forward. We haven't
seen combine results from a guy that
size in terms of Taylor since really
like Calvin Johnson is comparable to
him. What is it that that point in the
draft just the athleticism just
outweighs like maybe a more polished
passer like a Nusmeer in that situation?
>> Yeah. You know, I wouldn't necessarily
compare him to the other prospects other
than say that we felt like Talon's
makeup um you know, his physical. We
just think there's a lot to work with.
>> Yeah. Andrew,
>> I know obviously you guys don't have an
answer from Joel on in terms of his
future, but given the amount of
resources dedicated to the offensive
line that you guys have have obviously
done, is is there any thing to read into
there? I guess in terms of you guys in
terms of like maybe with the direction
you guys are heading as as far as the
offensive line is concerned,
>> I wouldn't say so. I think when we've
been at our best, when we had, you know,
when we had the best unit in the league,
um, we were deep. It wasn't just
quality, but it was it was depth as
well. And so, um, you know, there are a
couple positions that once you get past
this time of the year, you just can't
acquire till like really the next off
season. Um, and then the offensive line
position group, that's one of those
spots. So, when we can add players, you
know, the bigger guys that that are hard
to find, you know, we'll do that.
>> You were talking about Parker when you
drafted it. I think you said something
like you're he's exactly what you're
looking for. um what is it about him and
is the weight any concern for you?
>> Yeah, you know, we always, you know, and
and Hops even probably best at at saying
this, like, you know, if you didn't
know, you wouldn't be able to tell with
his, you know, with his play. Um, but
really the bigger thing is, and you
could see it when we had um when we had
JC here, when we had Nick Harris when he
was healthy, and then in Baltimore when
they had, you know, Tyler Linderbomb,
um, the centers that that can pull and
work at the second level and get to the
perimeter because of their athleticism
and speed, they they give you a lot of
optionality in the run game. And that's
something that Parker does very very
well. Also, we're excited about um you
know that part of his profile.
>> Can you talk about maybe the makeup of
your quarterback room right now?
Obviously, two really young guys, three
now really young guys, two that have
some experience and then Deshan, just
overall the just the makeup, the energy
of the room.
>> Yeah, I I mean, I think the three guys
that we've had here have worked really
hard and they've got along really well.
Um, we've been really pleased with the,
you know, early part of the offseason
program and we think, you know, Taylor
will really fit in nicely just because
of how he's wired, his work ethic. Um,
you know, so we're we're looking forward
to seeing that group progress over the
course of the spring and summer.
>> And do you feel like Deshawn
I know he was a really good mentor to
the younger guys last year and
everything. Do you think he'll be good
for someone like like Talon with his Pro
Bowl background and all of that?
>> Yeah, I like Deshawn's Deshawn's great
with his teammates. Um and and I I'd
imagine that would continue to be the
case. Um so that that group they they
work together really well and they get
along really well.
>> At this stage of the draft, how much
does a guy in sort of in relation to to
Justin Jefferson, how much does a guy
having that special teams quality and
that is a characteristic in their game
maybe like boost them on your board or
sort of fit into the picture when you're
thinking about value at this at this
stage?
>> It's definitely a factor. Um, it's not a
one-sizefits-all approach. You know, I
think with with Justin, he's a a DNA
match for this defense because, you
know, we'll prioritize speed, range,
athleticism, and sacrifice a little bit
of size because of how we play. Um, but
then also like his ability in in the
kicking game is is certainly a bonus um
because it gives a relatively high floor
for a year one role.
>> You folks right into the season that the
offseason is going to be mostly about
the offense, right? The resources. I I'm
just wondering when you were
interviewing Todd and talking to Todd
before he got the job, how much of that
was a discussion topic on how you're
going to fix it and exactly how he
thought you might be able to fix?
>> Yeah, we were transparent with all the
candidates we talked to about that part
of it. You know, we were honest with
where we were in our, you know, our
roster life cycle and said, "Hey, look
here. Here's how we've positioned
ourselves, you know, going into this
year and how here's how we generally uh
anticipate deploying the assets." So,
that's something that we were very open
at. I think to accept a job, you know,
this big as like a, you know, head coach
in the NFL, um, you know, when you're
walking into a team with transition,
like you have to have visibility in
terms of, you know, what, you know, what
that'll look like moving forward.
>> Andrew, um, you had some, uh, not draft
related, but, you had some a group of
players in for for tryyouts during the
baller mini camp. Are you planning on
did are you planning on keeping some
around continuing those tryyous signing
any of them? Have any decisions made?
>> Uh we have not signed any today. Um you
know that's probably TBD. I would not
anticipate that we're signing any
veterans in the short term. But you know
it's something that we could revisit as
we get through draft week and as we get
through the um undrafted free agent
signing process.
>> Does Taylor Green then complete the
quarterback room?
>> Uh yes. Yeah. Uh you know what? Let me
back up. I should have I I should have
learned the I' I've learned the hard way
not to say anything definitively.
The current plan is that we would roll
with those four. I can't predict if
something else comes up. So yes, that
would be the intention.
>> Off the bat, he has started so many
games in college. He's been around for a
long time. He's played a lot of
football. How did that maybe sort of
factor into your decision? you know, it
it's part of the equation, Mary Kay, but
I wouldn't say that it was, you know, by
any means like the heaviest weight or
the driving force, you know, behind the
decision. Um, but yeah, it it it does it
does play a role in
>> you feel like you construct like through
the draft, through the offse construct
this offensive line to make it conducive
to a Joel return if he decides that he
wants to come back.
>> Uh, I play this way. We'll never run
away from good players. Of all your
picks, which is the most surprising you
you got them right now?
>> That's a great question, Jeff.
>> Um, honestly, it's it's it's Eman. Like,
it it really it's Emanuel. Um,
that's the one that I I wouldn't have
anticipated that he would have been
available where where we selected him.
>> We so much about quarterback. So, when
you entered this weekend, did you think
you were going to take Tailon, but was
that part of the plan? I mean, I know I
know things changed, but like when you
envisioned it, was that
>> I'd say this like there was um
I don't know that you can predict day
three of the draft. Um we knew that
quarterback could have be one of the
positions as we thought through how day
three could play out that we could make
a selection. Um and he was certainly in
the pool of quarterbacks that obviously
he was in the pool of quarterbacks that
um could come in consideration depending
on how the board felt. But I I wouldn't
say it was like, okay, hey, look, you
can't be so strict with your planning
because you just you don't you don't
control how the names come off the come
off the board.